Guide to the Berkeley College, Yale University, Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Berkeley College, Yale University, photographs
1933-1997
RU 603
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
The collection contains photographs documenting the construction and renovation of Berkeley College. Included are interior and exterior views of courtyards, the Fellow's suite, the dining hall, and architectural details. The collection also contains prints of architect's drawings and plans.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in four series: I. Construction Progress Photographs, 1933-1934. II. General Views, 1934-1960. III. Oversize. IV. Slides and transparencies, and subsequent accession.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains photographs documenting the construction and renovation of Berkeley College. Included are interior and exterior views of courtyards, the Fellow's suite, the dining hall, and architectural details. The collection also contains prints of architect's drawings and plans.
College buildings -- Design and construction; Photographs; Berkeley College (Yale University); Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Student housing
- Construction progress photographs, 1933-1934; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The series consists of photographs documenting the excavation and construction of Berkeley College, Yale University.
  - Pre-construction, July 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Excavation, August 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Construction, September 1933- August 1934 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 8)
  - Exterior, September-October 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- General Views, 1934-circa 1960; Series II
  - Architect's drawings (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Exterior, general (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Exterior, South Court (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Exterior, North Court (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Interior, Dining Hall (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Interior, Fellow's Suite (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Interior, general (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Details (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Oversize, Series III
  - View (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Slides and transparencies, Series IV
  - Slides (Box 4)
  - Transparencies [glass slides] (Box CS10, Folder 194)
  - Transparencies [glass slides] (Box CS10, Folder 195)
  - Transparencies [glass slides] (Box CS10, Folder 196)
  - Transparencies [glass slides] (Box CS10, Folder 197)
- Renovation Photographs, circa 1997; Accession 2003-A-115
  - Photographs of the renovation of Berkeley College, circa 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)